I never dreamed before
（ミッちゃん）ハハハ…
まっ しゃーねぇな ハハハハ…
I'm gonna knock the door
into the world of perfect free
(You ain't no lonely!)
（コユキ）やめ…
You're gonna say I'm lying
やめろ～！
I'm gonna get the chance
I thought a chance is far from me
(You ain't no lonely!)
（学(まなぶ)）ん… ん？
（選手）うらぁっ！
I was made to hit in America
(I was made to hit in America)
You are the sun, you are the star
(To me, forever)
I was made to hit in America
(I was made to hit in America)
Oh well...
Stop...
Stop!
（真帆(まほ)の英語）
Koyuki is the best!
Have you lost your mind?
（竜介(りゅうすけ)の英語）
What the hell are you saying
all of a sudden?
I said Koyuki is the best.
The vocalist for your band's
gotta be Koyuki.
He's a genius. He's gonna
be a fucking great vocalist.
Hey, we're not talking about
making the choir here, understand?
Now really, you don't understand!
What are they fighting about?
I can't understand them at all.
何 ケンカしてんのかな
全然 分からないね
I think Koyuki will be great too!
（泉(いずみ)）
私も コユキがいいと思う
Huh?!
（泉）バンドのボーカル
The vocalist for the band.
I think Koyuki will be good!
私も コユキがいいと思うな
Vocalist?
ボーカル？
Koyuki and Chiba, huh?
コユキ… と千葉(ちば)か…
（千葉）あ～… ハグッ ん～っ
W-what? What're you looking at?!
（千葉）
な 何だよ 何見てんだよ！
ハァ～
（コユキ）ハァ…
Yukio! You have a letter from Hiro-kun!
（コユキの母）幸雄～！
ヒロ君から手紙来てるわよ～
"How are you, Yukio-kun?
I'm doing very well right now."
（ラジオの
チューニング音）
"I won the Kyushu
Piano Contest the other day!"
"Do you know how big that is?
I might even go to Vienna!"
"P.S. I bought the latest Sangokushi."
Let's see...
（コユキ）え～と…
"Dear Hiro-kun,"
“前略 ヒロ君 手紙ありがとう”
"Thank you for your letter.
I've started playing the guitar."
“実は僕 ギターを始めました”
"It's surprisingly easy to play."
“案外ギターって… 簡単ですね”
"I've mastered music played
by Van Halen, Steve Vai,
“ヴァン・ヘイレンも
スティーヴ・ヴァイも—”
“ポール・ギルバートも ヌーノも
ザック・ワイルドも…—”
Paul Gilbert, Nuno, Zakk Wylde,
and even Yot-chan..."
“ヨッちゃんも
すぐマスターできました”
“今 練習してるのは
「四季の歌」です”
"I'm practicing
'The Song of the Seasons' right now."
"Wouldn't it be great if we
could play together in Vienna?"
“ウィーンで
共演できるといいですね”
“同封した写真は—”
"The photo I've enclosed was taken
at the East Japan Guitar Awards
“総合体育館で開催された—”
held at the municipal gymnasium."
“東日本ギター・アワード
中学生部門で—”
"It's from when I won in
the middle school division."
“優勝した時のものです かしこ”
"Yours truly..."
Mom, I'm going to the gymnasium!
（コユキ）母さん 俺
ちょっと体育館 行ってくんねー
What am I doing anyway?
（コユキ）何してんだろ 俺…
It's almost summer vacation...
（コユキ）もうすぐ… 夏休み… か
All right! First, I'm gonna
find me a giant beetle!
よ～し
まずはクマゼミをゲットだ！
うっ… うわぁっ！
とっとと… はっ！
（国吉(くによし)ちえみの曲）
Today's cloudy skies
will clear up with time
Go for it, don't be tied down,
set yourself free
Feel free, yes,
the new tomorrow is wow wow
So cheer up,
because I want to see your smile
ハァ…
H-hello...
こんにちは～
あっ ご… ごめんなさい！
I-I'm sorry!
（女性）誰～？ 今の子
Who was that kid?
（竜介）ん～？ コユキ
Koyuki.
お前 そろそろ帰れば？
-About time you leave.
-Huh? Forget that kid.
（女性）え～
あんな子ほっといてさ…
Go home!
（竜介）帰れよ
（女性）私より大事なんだ
（竜介）ああ
He's more important than me?
Yeah.
（女性）きのうと全然違うんだね
You felt differently yesterday!
You were so nice yesterday...
きのうはさ
あんなに優しかったのに…
You're the pits!
あんたって サイテー
フン！
-Yo!
-I-I'm sorry!
（竜介）よう！
（コユキ）ごめん…
Granny's not here now.
Let's practice a song.
（竜介）
今 ばあちゃん いねえんだ
ちょっと歌 合わせてみようか
Ryusuke-kun...I...
（コユキ）竜介君！ 実は…
きょうは話があって来たんだ
I have to talk to you.
What is it?
（竜介）何だよ 話って？
Get the fuck outta here!
二度と… 来るな
Never come around again.
I'm so sorry!
ごめんなさいっ！
うわぁっ！
ごめんなさい…
ごめんなさい… うう…
I'm sorry...I'm sorry...
ごめん… ごめんなさいっ！
I'm sorry...I'm sorry!
I'm sorry...
ごめん… わっ！
All right!
（斎藤(さいとう)）いよ～し！
まずはプルブイつけて—
First, get the lane markers
and we'll go 200 meters four times!
200メートル ４本いくぞ～！
（男子部員）
えー！ マジっすか？
-Are you serious?!
-We'll die!
（女子部員１）死にます～
甘えは許さ～ん！
I won't allow any slacking!
This summer, we're gonna get
way better than the rival schools!
この夏休み中の練習で—
ライバル校にガツンと
差をつけるんだ！ ガハハハ…
（鈴木(すずき)）
あの… 顧問の私の方針は…
Umm...What about my plans
as team advisor?
アハッ アハッ アハッ
アハハハ…
Boy, that interim coach is tough.
（女子部員２）
厳しいね～ 臨時コーチ
It's only been two weeks,
but he's way more than interim!
週２のペースじゃ
臨時コーチとは言えないよ
（女子部員２）このままだと
退部者 続出するよ
If this keeps up, everyone will
quit the team! But he sure is tough!
しっかし タフだよねぇ
Saito-san is a fanatic who swims
over 30,000 meters every week!
（泉）なんたって斎藤さんは—
週に３万メートル以上 泳ぐ
バリバリのスイマーだからさ
It's like, is he really 44?!
（女子部員２）
ホントに44歳かよ みたいなー
By the way, isn't Koyuki-kun
joining the team?
ところでさ
コユキ君は入部しないの？
He's in a bit of a bind right now.
あいつ ちょっと大変なことに
なってるんだよね
（女子部員２）大変な… こと？
-Bind?
-Yeah.
I wonder if he's okay.
大丈夫かな… あいつ…
ブハァッ！
こらっ そこの女子２人～！
Hey, you two girls! No slacking!
サボってんじゃねぇぞ！
（２人）すいませーん
-Sorry!
Yukio, you have a letter from Hiro-kun!
"I'm shocked you started
playing the guitar."
（コユキの母）
幸雄～ ヒロ君から手紙よ
"But I bet you're still
no match for my piano skills."
"I wanna hear how good you are.
Play for me whenever I visit next."
"P.S. I didn't get to go to Vienna,
but I did visit Holland Town."
Huh? Koyuki-kun, right?
（斎藤）
あれ？ コユキ君… だよね？
（コユキ）あ… はい…
Yes.
（斎藤）どうかしたの？
あれからプールで全然見かけないね
Did something happen? I haven't
seen you at the pool since then.
No.
You play the guitar?
（斎藤）ギター弾くのかい？
Err...no...
（コユキ）いや…
-This is...
-Oh boy, that's bad!
これ…
（斎藤）うわー こりゃひどいなぁ
Yes...
（コユキ）そうなんです
一度 壊れたら…
Once it's broken...
Broken things can't be fixed.
壊れた物は… 直りません
-I wonder about that.
-Huh?
（斎藤）そうかな？
（コユキ）えっ
This guitar can probably be fixed.
（斎藤）たぶん直るよ このギター
My friend will do it for cheap.
Give it a month and it'll be fixed.
僕の知り合いなら安くしてくれるし
１か月もみてれば大丈夫！
It can be fixed?
直る…
Saito-san...
斎藤さん
フフ… こう見えても僕は—
I may not look like it,
but British rock changed my life.
ブリティッシュロックに
人生を変えられた男なんだ
Saito-san...
斎藤さん…
Poor guitar, if you throw it away.
ギターだって捨てられたら
かわいそうだよ
そのギター持って
いつでも遊びに来なさい
Come on over anytime,
and bring that guitar.
If you'd like, I'd be happy to teach you.
僕でよければ
教えてあげてもいいよ
See you!
All right.
（コユキ）よしっ
This is pitiful...
はかないな…
About Koyuki...
（泉）コユキのことなんだけど…
That guitar was given to me by Eddie.
（竜介）あのギターは…
エディにもらったギターなんだ
No one would give me the time of day...
誰にも相手にして
もらえないでいた—
And it was Eddie who took the time
to talk to this Japanese kid.
日本人の俺に話しかけて
くれたのが… エディだった
But even Koyuki...
（泉）でも コユキだって…
Ryusuke-kun...
竜介君…
Hey! Look, look!
（千葉）お～い 見て 見てぇ～！
ヘヘヘ～
おっとと…
ヘヘヘヘ…
ちょっと頂いてきましたよーん
Look what I got!
-Hey, Ryusuke! Help me!
-Huh?
おい竜介 ピストン輸送手伝え！
（竜介）は？
Here you are, Izumi-chan!
は～い 泉ちゃーん！
Oh, thanks...
あ… どうも
（千葉）いいの いいの～
-Don't mention it!
-Huh? What about for me?
（カヨ）あれっ 私のはー？
-It was hilarious the other day...
-Huh?
（千葉）この前 おっかしくてさー
（泉・カヨ）はあ…
（千葉）竜介のヤツ
納豆 食ったことなくってさー
Ryusuke's never eaten natto in his life.
-Huh?! You serious?!
-So
（カヨ）えー マジー？
（千葉）でさー
Hey. It's almost time.
（竜介）おい そろそろだぞ
（泉・カヨ）うん
-Right.
（千葉）えー ライブなんて
どーでもいいじゃん！
Man, who cares about the concert?
-Don't you want to make
summer memories with me?
-Let's go!
それよりぃ 僕と
夏の思い出づくりしませんかー？
（竜介）行くぞ！
それよりぃ 僕と
夏の思い出づくりしませんかー？
Hey! I'm coming, too! C'mon!
It'd be the perfect double date!
おーい！ 俺も行く！
あ～！
２対２で ちょうどいいのに…
Can't think of a band without him.
彼なしのバンドは考えられない！
ああ 確かにファンキーだなー
Yeah, definitely funky.
（学）ハッハッハ
ホント ヘッタクソなボーカルだぜ
Man, the vocals were terrible!
（ボーカル）何だ おめぇ！
What the hell-?!
With vocals like that,
I feel sorry for Taira.
（学）そんなボーカルじゃ
平(たいら)君がマジもったいないよー
Why you-!
貴様…
Good evening, everyone!
（学）みんな こんばんはー！
I'm Manabu and I used to
do vocals with The Crowd!
クラウドでボーカルやってた
学でーす
（女性客１）学ー！
（女性客２）学 歌ってー！
-Manabu!
-Sing for us!
You're so cool!
（女性客３）カッコいい～！
Switch with me, you're terrible.
代わりな ヘッタクソ君
Why you-!
ちくしょー！ オラァ！
おっ！ お… おわっ！
（女性客４）キャーッ
Sing, Manabu!
Ryusuke-kun...
（泉）竜介君
I know. This was Eiji's idea.
（竜介）
そうだ これは栄二(えいじ)のアイデアだな
Well, since I'm on stage,
maybe I'll sing.
（学）んー せっかくだから
歌っちゃおうかなー
The Music Men are here,
じゃあ ミュージックマンズも
カバーしてる—
so maybe I'll sing "Journey"
by the Heartbreakers!
ハートブレイカーズの
「ジャーニー」をプレゼント！
What'll we do?
（メンバー）どうする？
Hurry and sing!
Who's calling my name?
I hear the voice of legends
What do I want?
Static emotion comes down
Did I have the dream?
Am I misunderstood?
What do I want?
Static emotion comes down
-I'm going home.
-What?
帰るわ 俺
（竜介）何っ？
I don't know what's good about him at all.
どこがいいのか全然分かんねえよ
"Saito Paper Company"
That's it! F is played by
pressing down with your index finger.
（斎藤）そうそう Ｆは人さし指の
側面を使って押さえるんだよ
That's it! F is played by
pressing down with your index finger.
Hmm...pretty good.
んー… いいんじゃないかな
Really?
（コユキ）本当？
だいぶ よくなってるよ
音が出るようになったでしょ
You're progressing nicely.
You can make sounds now.
Yeah.
うん よく使うコードは
押さえられるようになったから—
Now that you've gotten
the hang of common chords,
let's try to play continuously.
今度は 連続して鳴らしてみようか
Uhh...My fingers...
えー… 指が…
Hurt, don't they?
痛いよねぇ
But if you give up now,
you won't make it with girls.
でも ここで めげてちゃ
女の子にはモテないぞ
No, that's not what I-
（コユキ）
いや そういうことじゃ…
Koyuki-kun. Observe.
コユキ君 見たまえ！
フフフフ…
（コユキ）す… すごい
T-that's amazing!
Koyuki-kun, come with me.
（斎藤）コユキ君 ついて来たまえ
Okay.
（コユキ）はい
When I got injured and had
my Olympic dreams shattered,
（斎藤）ケガで
オリンピックの夢が破れた時—
I felt so sorry for myself,
and my only consolation...
自暴自棄になっていた僕を
慰めてくれたのは…
んんっ ん… いよっ
ロックと… ギターだった
...was guitars!
Which one do you like, Koyuki-kun?
コユキ君は どっちがいいかな？
あっ！ 左のギター
竜介君のと同じ形だ
The guitar on the left is
the same shape as Ryusuke-kun's!
Oh...I'll bet that one
is a Gibson Les Paul.
ほう！ その子は たぶん
ギブソンのレスポールだね
僕のは ギブソンの偽物で
“ティブソン”のレスポール
But mine is a fake
called the Tibson Les Paul.
１ドル360円の時代には
高くて本物には手が出なかった
When it was 360 yen to the dollar,
I couldn't afford the real McCoy.
（コユキ）あー… ティブソン？
Tibson?
Now then...I'll let you
borrow this Les Paul.
それじゃあ このレスポール
貸してあげるよ
Huh?! Are you sure?!
（コユキ）え！ いいんですか？
You'll also need a tuning machine,
and...an amp.
あとは… チューニングマシンと…
アンプか
（ペイジ）アホウ！ アホアホー
ア～ホ ア～ホ
Fool! Fool! Fool! Fool! Fool!
ア～ホ アッホー
"My name is Page."
Fool! Fool! Fool! Fool! Fool!
-Fool! Fool! Fool! Fool! Fool!
-Page?
（コユキ）ペイジ？
Ever heard of a band
called the Rocket Boys?
コユキ君はロケットボーイズって
バンド 知ってるかな？
（ペイジ）アホウ！
Fool!
They're a mystery British group,
overshadowed by the Beatles,
（斎藤）ビートルズの影に隠れ—
たった１枚のアルバムを残し
解散した—
who recorded one album
and then broke up.
幻のブリティッシュバンドなんだ
They're the teachers of my soul.
僕の心の師匠だ
Follow me
Baby, I won't let you leave
if you believe in me
-And I always set you free
from all those yesteryears
-A-amazing!
（コユキ）す… すごいよ
こんな鳥
テレビでも見たことないです！
-And I always set you free
from all those yesteryears
-I've never seen a bird like that,
even on TV.
（斎藤）フフフ…
ペイジはね 44歳 独身貴族—
That's Page.
The one and only friend of Kenichi Saito,
age 44 and unmarried.
斎藤研一の
唯一無二の心の友なんだよ
Fool!
（ペイジ）アホウ！
Making him sing is my goal.
（斎藤）こいつを歌わせるのが
僕の悲願なんだ！
Dammit!
ちくしょーっ！ うぐぐ…
（コユキ）うわぁっ
He'll only respond to great music!
こいつは すばらしい演奏にしか
さえずらないんだ
Koyuki-kun! Let's do our best
to make Page sing!
コユキ君！
ペイジをさえずらせる日まで
頑張ろうじゃないか！
All right! If I'm going to try,
I may as well give it my best!
はい！ やるからには
本気でやらないと！
That's the spirit, Koyuki-kun!
（斎藤）いいぞ！ コユキ君！
Just wait! We'll make him sing for us!
鳴かぬなら 鳴かせてみせるぞ
この鳥めー！
Yes! Atta boy, Koyuki-kun!
（斎藤）
そうだ！ その意気だ コユキ君！
Of the three feudal generals,
I like Nobunaga the best.
戦国武将で好きなのは信長だけど…
（ペイジ）アホーッ
Fool!
（斎藤）それじゃ
きょうの おさらいをしましょう
Okay then, let's start today's practice!
All right! Please teach me!
（コユキ）はい！ お願いします！
A!
（斎藤）Ａ！ Ｄ！ Ｇ！ Ｆ！
D!
G!
F!
Another minute
Feelin' so fine
You turn the freeze
into warm light
Had a premonition
I've been waitin' ever since
My world comin' down
It's got me spinnin' 'round
If you really wanna fly
you gotta let go
Simply the most
big sensation
(once you're here you won't go back)
She's really pretty
One-eyed vision
(lose the fear it don't come back)
Little sister showed me
Really took me for a ride
My world comin' down
(once you're here you won't go back)
(lose the fear it don't come back)
The road comes to a fork.
（千葉）二股が… バレました
"Next Episode"
The road comes to a fork.
Isn't love so painful?
恋愛は切ないよね… ね？